<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hieu&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hieu&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 10:32:12 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris Week2</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 10:32:12 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w2/</guid>
      <description>Counting is the religion of this generation, its hope and salvation.
&amp;ndash; Gertrude Stein (1874–1946)
 1. The Theory Key concepts: Binary numbers, binary addition, the two&amp;rsquo;s complement method, half-adders, full-adders, n-bit adders, counters, Arithmetic Logic Unit (ALU), combinational logic.
After finishing week 1 rather quick, i was eager to start week 2 and looking forward to next type of chips. The theory is presented in such an easy way that i can do arithmetic calculation base 2 and 10, negative numbers right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris Intro</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 21:50:13 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris/</guid>
      <description>Course Intro. Excited?
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris Week1</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 10:01:17 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w1/</guid>
      <description>What i have learnt in this week.
1.Boolean laws Any boolean function can be represented using an expression containing only NAND operations.
Proof:  NOT(x) = (x NAND x)
 (x AND y) = NOT(x NAND y)
  2.Hardware description language  In computer engineering, a hardware description language is a specialized computer language used to describe the structure and behavior of electronic circuits, and most commonly, digital logic circuits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Editor</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/vim-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 21:29:33 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/vim-editor/</guid>
      <description>Well, recently i often work with docker and control config on server, i suffered a lot due to my weakness regards vim usage on linux.
Turn out, these basic things prove significant as you&amp;rsquo;d like to pursue DevOps career.
It would be great to improve on my vim skill by taking note down the essential of this powerful editor. Moreover, there is one tutor right in your Ubuntu terminal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Online Courses</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/online-cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 08:20:40 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/online-cert/</guid>
      <description> 2019  Build a Modern Computer from First Principles: From Nand to Tetris (Project-Centered Course), Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Current. Programming with Google Go Specialization, UCI, July 2019 Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, MIT, Summer 2019  2018  An Introduction to Hyperledger Technologies, LinuxFoundationX, June 2018 Docker Essentials, IBM, May 2018 IBM Blockchain Foundation Developer, IBM, Apr 2018 Learning How to Learn, McMaster University &amp;amp; University of California San Diego, Apr 2018  2017  Using Python to Access Web Data, U-M, Oct 2017 Python Data Structures, U-M, Oct 2017 Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python), U-M, Oct 2017 Using Databases with Python, U-M, Nov 2017  2016  Regression Modeling in Practice, Wesleyan University, Sep 2016 Data Analysis Tools, Wesleyan University, Sep 2016 Excel to MySQL Analytic Techniques for Business Specialization, Duke University, July 2016  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive Command</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/archive-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:49:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/archive-command/</guid>
      <description>There are many types of compress file, with each type we should have different command to interact with it. To find which archive type we are working with, use file command.
$ file a.zip a.zip: Zip archive data, at least v1.0 to extract $ file b.tar b.tar: POSIX tar archive (GNU) $ file c.tar.gz c.tar.gz: gzip compressed data, last modified: Tue Aug 20 04:33:47 2019, from Unix Here are some most common types i&amp;rsquo;ve been working with recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post!</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 14:23:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post, how exciting!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>