<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hieu&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hieu&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 21:36:01 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Without CS degree</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/without-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 21:36:01 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/without-cs/</guid>
      <description>I don’t have a CS degree so I&amp;rsquo;ve had to learn on my own. (@RandallKanna)
 This is the title of a twitter thread which is true for me. I found this thread a world of useful resources that a blog post to document them for later use is a good idea. Below are the original post and the links to the courses/material/videos.
 Start with a great intro course to get you excited about learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris W5</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 10:26:08 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w5/</guid>
      <description>Last week, my wife came to BKK to see me and we had a wonderful short trip to Koh Lan island just 40 minutes away from Pattaya. It had been almost 2 months since we last met when i was in Vietnam back then, so that we did enjoyed our time together. Moreover, we accompanied 2 great friends in Son and Tik and all four of us took photos, shared stories and laughed so hard in that sea food restaurant while playing Tik-guessing game and drinking beers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris W4</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 16:55:58 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w4/</guid>
      <description>Background
Every hardware platform is designed to execute commands in a certain machine language, expressed using agreed-upon binary codes. Writing programs directly in binary code is a possible, yet unnecessary. Instead, we can write such programs using a low-level symbolic language, called assembly, and have them translated into binary code by a program called assembler.
 Machine Language After making the gates and chips in previous 3 weeks, i had a chance to learn more about the machine language which is in binary form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris Week3</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 10:59:20 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w3/</guid>
      <description>Background
The computer&amp;rsquo;s main memory, also called Random Access Memory, or RAM, is an addressable sequence of n-bit registers, each designed to hold an n-bit value. In this project you will gradually build a RAM unit. This involves two main issues: (i) how to use gate logic to store bits persistently, over time, and (ii) how to use gate logic to locate (&amp;ldquo;address&amp;rdquo;) the memory register on which we wish to operate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris Week2</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 10:32:12 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w2/</guid>
      <description>Background
The centerpiece of the computer&amp;rsquo;s architecture is the CPU, or Central Processing Unit, and the centerpiece of the CPU is the ALU, or Arithmetic-Logic Unit. In this project you will gradually build a set of chips, culminating in the construction of the ALU chip of the Hack computer. All the chips built in this project are standard, except for the ALU itself, which differs from one computer architecture to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris Intro</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 21:50:13 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris/</guid>
      <description>Course Intro. Excited?
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nand2tetris Week1</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 10:01:17 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/nand/nand2tetris-w1/</guid>
      <description>Background
A typical computer architecture is based on a set of elementary logic gates like And, Or, Mux, etc., as well as their bit-wise versions And16, Or16, Mux16, etc. (assuming a 16-bit machine). This project engages you in the construction of a typical set of basic logic gates. These gates form the elementary building blocks from which more complex chips will be later constructed.
 Here is what i have learnt in this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vim Editor</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/vim-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 21:29:33 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/vim-editor/</guid>
      <description>Well, recently i often work with docker and control config on server, i suffered a lot due to my weakness regards vim usage on linux.
Turn out, these basic things prove significant as you&amp;rsquo;d like to pursue DevOps career.
It would be great to improve on my vim skill by taking note down the essential of this powerful editor. Moreover, there is one tutor right in your Ubuntu terminal.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get started and hope you learn something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Online Courses</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/online-cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 08:20:40 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/online-cert/</guid>
      <description>2019  Build a Modern Computer from First Principles: From Nand to Tetris (Project-Centered Course), Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Current. Programming with Google Go Specialization, UCI, July 2019 Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs, MIT, Summer 2019  2018  An Introduction to Hyperledger Technologies, LinuxFoundationX, June 2018 Docker Essentials, IBM, May 2018 IBM Blockchain Foundation Developer, IBM, Apr 2018 Learning How to Learn, McMaster University &amp;amp; University of California San Diego, Apr 2018  2017  Using Python to Access Web Data, U-M, Oct 2017 Python Data Structures, U-M, Oct 2017 Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python), U-M, Oct 2017 Using Databases with Python, U-M, Nov 2017  2016  Regression Modeling in Practice, Wesleyan University, Sep 2016 Data Analysis Tools, Wesleyan University, Sep 2016 Excel to MySQL Analytic Techniques for Business Specialization, Duke University, July 2016  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive Command</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/archive-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 10:49:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/archive-command/</guid>
      <description>There are many types of compress file, with each type we should have different command to interact with it. To find which archive type we are working with, use file command.
$ file a.zip a.zip: Zip archive data, at least v1.0 to extract $ file b.tar b.tar: POSIX tar archive (GNU) $ file c.tar.gz c.tar.gz: gzip compressed data, last modified: Tue Aug 20 04:33:47 2019, from Unix Here are some most common types i&amp;rsquo;ve been working with recently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post!</title>
      <link>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 14:23:54 +0700</pubDate>
      <author>hieuletrung102@gmail.com (Hieu Le)</author>
      <guid>https://hieutle2011.github.io/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>This is my first post, how exciting!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>